MAINGI JOSEPH M,

P.O.BOX 128-00218,

LIMURU.

TEL: 0729-079030.

Email: Maingijoseph11@gmail.com

**20th JANUARY, 2021** 

### RADIO AFRICA LIMITED,

Email: info@radioafricagroup.co.ke,

Lion Place, Waiyaki Way, Westlands,

Tel: +254- 711 046 000

NAIROBI-KENYA.

Dear Sir/Madam,

### RE: APPLICATION FOR A JOB AS A RADIO PRESENTER

Kind reference is made to the above subject matter with request of consideration to your office. This follows an advert ran in your radio station and as such as I would wish to express my passionate interest.

I am Maingi Joseph Mbugua, aged 30.

My vision has always been to be part of an organization which has high reputation with high moral values and ethics that can grant me an opportunity in our today's society. I am a graduate from the University having done a diploma in finance with reputable experience in Journalism and Mass Media.

This course has prepared me in different fields whereby I can work in the finance department, Public Relations department or any Media related field. Currently I am television reporter at HOPE TV as well as a Radio co-host and sport analyst on hope fm.

In granting my humble request you are assured of high level of discipline, hard work, commitment, responsible and willing to learn from your well-equipped and knowledgeable staff and offer my services to your organization. I believe that sharing my skills; will see the organization grow from one step to another.

I am a script writer in plays, poems, and short films. I am willing to be part of your organization and give my services to your institution. I will be happy to be called for an interview at your best convenience time

Your response will be highly appreciated.

Kind regards,

Maingi Joseph Mbugua.

# Joseph Maingi Mbugua

(+254) 729079030 (+254) 101079030 128-00217 Limuru, Kenya

maingijoseph11@gmail.com

### **EDUCATION**

# St Paul's University-Kenya

Diploma in finance, 2012

- Credit
- Research Project; impact of youth unemployment in the economy.
- Winner; Kenya Christian universities alcohol and drug abuse debate, 2014.

### **Gichuru High School**

Kenya Certificate of Secondary Education, KCSE, 2008

- Mean Grade; **B**-
- Best overall student

### RELEVANT EXPERIENCE

### Hope media Kenya, Nairobi, November 2016 to

Date

News reporter and Radio co-host

- Presenting a weekly sports show dubbed Saturday sports and request.
- Creating content for sports analysis and news.
- News reporting and production
- Feature stories production

# Kenya broadcasting corporation (KBC), Nairobi, November 2013 to

August 2017 Television host (abled differently)

- Presenting a television show dubbed abled-differently
- Script and content development

### Wing matt supermarket Limuru town, June 2012 - May 2013

Manager and stock maintenance

- Overseeing all activities for the supermarket (customer care, requisition of orders, cash payment, and bank deposits) Coordinate all the day to day affairs of the supermarket.
- Coordinate in Liaison with the premises owner all the supermarket transaction.

# St Paul's University-light FM, Main campus-Limuru, February 2012- December 2012 Radio host and editor

- Presenter of a Swahili program dubbed miondoko east afrika.
- Writer and newspaper editor of the university newspaper the canvas.
- Video and sound editor in the videography and film section.
- Mentor and trainer for new presenter in the radio section.

### Kenya Agricultural and Livestock Research Organization,- Tigoni Centre-Limuru,

November 2013 to August 2017

Research Consultant

- Analyzing data on potato and land usage in Kiambu, Nyandarua, Meru, Embu, Nakuru and Mombasa counties.
- Designing environmental and socio-economic data collection tools.
- Supervising research and data collection teams.
- Writing weekly reports on research undertakings and target reviews.

### RELEVANT SECTION—COMMUNITY SERVICE

# **Community Service**

- **June 2009-2014:** Organized the Henry Wanyoike hope for the future run.
- **Aug 2017:** Participated in charity visit to Alpha Joy Children's Home in Nairobi

### **Membership**

- Youth and Leadership: chair person, P.C.E.A Kabuku youth, Limuru.
- **Community Development**: A member of the Kenya Red Cross Society, Limuru Branch.
- **Conservation:** A member of the Kenya scout association since March 2014.
- **Mentorship:** A member of the Limuru Joint University Students Association, **LIJUSA**

#### **SKILLS & INTERESTS**

- Computer skills Excellent use of windows 8 & 10 OS, Microsoft office, Internet
- Data Management and Analysis skills
- Communication languages- English and Swahili

- Topical Interest: Environmental conservation
- Writing scripts for poems, plays, comedies and short movies

### **REFERENCES**

# 1. Mrs. Grace Mutiso Kirwaye

Station Manager,

HOPE FM

Phone: +254 720389774

Email: GKirwaye@hopefm.org

# 2. Mr. Tony Omondi,

News Editor,

HOPE FM/TV

Phone: +254 707978915

Email: TOmondi@hopefm.org

# 3. Mrs. Jackie Njagi

Lidibwi. Television

producer,

Kenya Broadcasting Coporation (KBC), Phone: +254 721839152

Email: undisalj@gmail.com